
//2006-05-29 by Luis Cobian

The original indy 10 uses 3 properties called

onWork, OnBeginWork and OnEndWork, but they use integers. 
Because the FTP can be using Large Streams of files, 
the program would generate an exception while
trying to transfer large files with an OnWork event assigned.

I have done changes in IdComponent.pas for OnWork and OnWorkBegin 
to use int64. 

You need to patch indy:

* Substitute the existing idComponent.pas with the one provided
here.

Another fixed bug: The date of an e-mail was using LocalTime + 2h.

* Substitute the idSysVCL with the one provide here

* Recompile the whole indy package