
* Chinese- simplified language updated
* Portuguese-br language updated
* Romanian language added
* French translation updated
* Russian translation updated
* Some errors in the english tutorial have been corrected
* Swedish language updated

2007-03-21 Version 8.4.0.198

* The program is now 100% compatible with Microsoft Windows Vista
* A new Interprocess communication method using named pipes has been added (for Vista)
* German 2 translation updated.

2007-03-07 Version 8.3.0.189

* Fixed a bug that prevented the program to use SMTP servers with authentication
* Some problems with permissions on Vista running under User Account Control have been fixed. Note that the program is NOT 100% Vista compatible yet
* The Update server used to hang if the log file got to big
* The log file of the update server is now renamed when it's size = 1 GB
* A buf fixed when detecting Vista

2007-02-15 Version 8.2.0.186

* Fixed a bug that prevented some directories to be deleted
* A new slovenian translation has been included
* Hungarian language updated

2007-02-03 Version 8.2.0.179

* HOTFIX, IMPORTANT UPDATE: In very strange cases, whhen downloading from an FTP site, if some exception was arised and the program was running as a service, the program could potentially corrupt the System32 directory. FIXED.
* French language updated
* Swedish language added
* Taiwan language updated
* Portuguese-pt language updated

2007-01-26 Version 8.2.0.173

* This is the LAST version directly updated and distributed by Luis Cobian. The original author has decided to make the program Open Source and it's time to other people to take over the development. Thank you a lot for all these years! 
* Fixed a refreshing bug in the standalone decryptor. 
* Russian language updated
* Danish language updated
* Italian language updated
* Portugese-brazil language updated
* Portugese-Pt language updated 
* Indonesian language updated
* Polish language updated

2006-11-16 Version 8.2.0.171

* If the engine or the interface cannot access the temporary directory, the program will change it automatically and log a warning
* If the user cancels the backup, and the shutdown flag is set, the program will NOT shutdown the computer
* The time elapsed for a backup is now shown as hh:mm:ss
* Fixed a problem when deleting read-only directories
* Dutch language updated
* German 2 translation updated
* Indonesian language updated
* Finnish translation added
* The css of the help file works now fine in Firefox
* French tutorial added
* French help added
* French language updated
* Portuguese files updated
* Russian translation updated
* Chinese simplified language added
* Help file updated

2006-08-25 Version 8.1.0.162

* Fixed a problem with the security permissions for the log file
* The log file lives now in the DB subdirectory.
* The program deletes now backups which have the "Read only attribute" set
* The color of the progress bar for the Total percent of the operation has been changed to brown when active
* Danish language added
* French language updated
* Polish language updated
* Russian language updated
* Chinese - Traditional language added

2006-08-07 Version 8.0.0.151


* Copying a root directory (C:\, for example) copied also it's attributes, making the destination hidden. Fixed.
* The attributes and permissions of a directory are now copied after the contain was copied.

2006-08-07 Version 8.0.0.149

* The caption of the Select directory dialog has been fixed
* The date/time of the mail send by the program is now correctly set.
* Tahoma is now the default font for the interface
* The default color of the hints is now the system default
* Portugese (Portugal) version added
* Polish language added
* The catalonian and portugese files have been renamed to exclude the accents in the file names (there are problems in some chinese systems with this)
* Czech language updated
* Italian language added
* Hungarian language added
* Alternative german language added
* French language updated
* German language updated
* Indonesian language added
* Dutch language files updated
* Dutch help file added

2006-06-27 Version 8.0.0.146

* I'm off to Mallorca for a couple of weeks of vacation. Will be back in the middle of July. Please use ONLY the support forum for questions. They will be answered when I come back.
* The program now correctly copies the attributes of the directories as well
* The Copy NTFS permissions is now set to false by default for new installations
* Using include masks with several sources in compressed backups resulted in the program backing up more files than it was needed. Fixed.
* Hungarian language updated
* Portuguese language updated
* French language updated

2006-06-26 Version 8.0.0.142

* The zip operation now correctly uses the temporary directory
* The user interface remembers now the last used directory
* Some controls have been better centered
* The decryptor warns now if the destination and the source are the same
* Russian language updated
* Dutch tutorial added
* Portuguese language updated

2006-06-22 Version 8.0.0.138

* The masks logic has been re-visited. Better masks support
* Decrypting files restores now the time stamp and the attributes of the original file
* A new parameter %COMPUTERNAMENOSPACES has been added
* Some cosmetical fixes done 
* Dutch language updated
* Some errors in the help file have been fixed
* Portuguese language updated

2006-06-20 Version 8.0.0.136

* The Services' window remembers now the position
* The backup properties dialog uses now the Show grid setting
* A "Find Next" button has been added to the Translator tool.
* The conditions to copy open files when possibly are now less restrictive.
* Some menu items were not translated correctly. Fixed.
* Selecting all the text in the log tab sets now the focus to the log area first.
* Some changes done in the authentication mechanism for SMTP
* The width of some controls has been adjusted to fit the Russian translation 
* Russian translation added
* Slovenian language added
* Portuguese language added
* Catalonian language added

2006-06-20 Version 8.0.0.134

* A new option was added to show the grid lines for the lists
* The default log font has been changed to Courier New
* A warning is now shown in the installer for the translators
* Some changes done in the english and spanish translation
* Hungarian translator added

2006-06-15 Version 8.0.0.132

* The task properties dialog displayed the wrong text for inclusion masks
* French translation updated
* The event "Add pause" displayed the wrong caption
* Trying to update a split archive gave of course an error. Now the program forces a full backup instead.
* The Cancel and OK button on the task properties never was translated. Fixed.

2006-06-14 Version 8.0.0.129

* Fixed a bug with the "Save list  as" menu
* Some changes done in the spanish translation
* You can now copy from the program's browser
* French translation updated
* A partially done czech language translation added

2006-06-12 Version 8.0.0.126

* Fixed a problem with permissions with the main list
* Fixed a problem with permissions with the update ini file
* Non-critical errors are not shown in the total error count
* French translation added
* German translation added
* Dutch translation added

2006-06-07 Version 8.0.0.121

* The program now imports lists from previous versions with FTP sources or destinations correctly

2006-06-05 Version 8.0.0.118

* Installing the service under a local account resulted in a "No mapping" error. Fixed
* The ExecuteAndWait event was not working well when the program was working as a service. Fixed.
* The program was ignoring the setting "Mail if errors only". Fixed
* If the backspace key was pressed on the internal browser, 2 characters were removed. Fixed
* Some grammatical errors in the tutorial have been corrected.
* The program shows now the update information in a better way

2006-06-02 Version 8.0.0.109

* More functionality added to the mask logic

2006-06-01 Version 8.0.0.108

* The exclusions/inclusions mask were not working at all. The basic functionality has been fixed. More to come in this field.
* The error No argument for format '%s'  was shown while a download failed. Fixed.
* The program now copies the permissions of the directories as well

2006-05-31 Version 8.0.0.105

* The program had sometimes problems detecting UNC directories. Fixed
* The program now assigns Full Control for all users to the DB and Settings subdirectory. Needed for multiuser access.
* backing up a whole drive like C:\ resulted in an invalid directory name. Fixed
* The toolbar buttons are now displayed as 32x32 buttons and not as 48x48

2006-05-30 Version 8.0.0.99

* The FTP test works could not create a test with timestamps in the file name. Fixed
* The setup program now correctly installs the UI manifest
* The visual XP style works now correctly
* The archive comment was not correctly translated

2006-05-24  %PROGRAMNAME% has been released

A whole new version "Black moon" is released with a LOT of changes:

* Unicode support for ALL the operations (except compression and FTP)
* Memory Mapped files is now used as IPC
* Passwords are now encrypted using Blowfish 128bits
* Added an encryption method:  RSA/Rijndael (1024 Asymmetric key/256-bit encryption)
* Now you can close a program using class names
* The after backup events are now ALWAYS executed
* Now you can impersonate individual users for individual tasks
* The limit of for copy of files with a total path length of 255 characters is now gone. The new limit is 32000 characters
* Better SQX error handling
* Now you can transfer large files (> 2 GB) with FTP
* This version runs only in NT based systems
* The mirroring effect that you got while compressing AND overwriting has been thankfully eliminated.

**************************************************************************
**************************************************************************

2006-04-18 Version 7.6.0.351

* Some very important changes in the encryption methods have been done.
In the pass, some problems could arise if you were encrypting files with a size of 2GB or larger. This is now fixed.
For compatibibility with the new method introduced in Black Moon, the encryption is now done using unicode passphrases.
Of course, the decryptor has been updated to handle the new and the obsolete methods.

Version 7.4.5.349

* Support for the new Live update service (v2) has been added
* When the source of a backup contained a large number of files, and several tasks started at the same time, those tasks were ignored because the program was busy counting files. FIXED. 
* Esperanto translation added
* Russian language updated
* A NEW portuguese-brazilian translation has been added
* Italian translation updated

2006-03-29 Version 7.4.5.348

* The ShutDown procedure displayed the "It's safe to shutdown Windows" screen. Should be fixed now.
* Check the program homepage for info about Cobian Backup Black Moon

2006-02-28. Version 7.4.5.347

* No more big updates will be done for version 7. The new version "Black Moon', unicode only will be the next release.
* Italian help file updated
* Italian language updated
* Russian language updated
* Deutsch language updated

2006-01-20 Version 7.4.5.345

* This is the LAST OFFICIAL version of Cobian Backup before it's going to Open Source.
I am letting this program go and it's time for other to carry on, or time for the program to rest in peace.
Farwell. See the official statement in my website.
* Incomplete russian translation added
* A little memory leak was fixed
* Swedish language updated
* Polish language updated
* The "Don't compress extensions" hint is now visible
* Dutch language files updated
* Hungarian language updated
* French translaton updated
* German language updated

2005-12-13 Version 7.4.5.343

* A test button has been added to test the SMTP and FTP settings 
* Now you can pass the source, directory or Task name as parameters to an Execute or Execute and wait event (see help file under Tasks)
* Now you can reorder the events by right-clicking on some event and choosing Move up or Move down
* Bug with creating multi-volume archive larger than 4Gb is fixed
* Help file and some tooltips have been updated
* Czech  language updated
* Hungarian language updated
* Swedish language added
* German language updated
* Hungarian language updated
* The FAQ has been updated
* SSL libraries updated

2005-11-28 Version 7.4.5.335

* The program can now copy NTFS permissions (unchecked by default)
* The program can now automatically convert mapped drives into UNC paths
* The problem when the program erroneously reports "The archive doesn't contain any files and has been deleted" is hopefully fixed 
* The "Autoexecute missed backups" ignores now the disabled tasks.
* Catalan language updated
* The "Close program" event gives you now a possibility to forcibly close an application with unsaved data or to kill it.

2005-11-23 Version 7.4.0.323

* AT LAST, a service can now stop and start programs in the visible desktop. YESSSSSSSSSSS!!!!!!
* Spanish language updated
* Euskera (vasque) language added
* The "Do not reset archive attributes" is now a Task setting, not a global option
* The decompressor can now ignore the log messages that don't contain errors
* The decompressor clears now the log before an operation begins
* Italian translation updated

2005-11-16 Version 7.3.0.310

* Now you can check the CRC of the files copied WITHOUT compression. This makes the backup 3 times slower but much reliable.
* The autostart for the user interface as a service can now be controlled from the options dialog
* The restart/shutdown events works now as a service even when no user is logged on
* The restart/shutdown events ask now if you want to close applications which contain unsaved data
* The restart/shutdown function works now fine in Windows 9x
* The setup program shows now  a warning about Zone Alarm
* Fixed a bug when saving a list with another name. The task ID is now correctly changed, preventing the 2 lists to use the same task history
* French help file updated.
* Hungarian language updated.
* Hungarian help file added
* Dutch language and FAQ updated
* French language updated
* German language updated
* Czech language updated
* A bug in the application caption is fixed
* The list of ASCII FTP extensions has been updated

2005-11-02 version 7.1.1.298

* Bug with adding more than 65535 files to an archive smaller than 4Gb is fixed
* Hungarian translation updated
* A new option has been added to start the missed backups without warning
* The parameter -bu can now be passed to the user interface (cobui.exe). This way, -bu will even work with services
* Fixed a problem with the Start menu icons in Windows 95/98/ME
* German translation updated.
* Slovakian language added, thanks to Rasto Cyprich

2005-10-18 Version 7.1.0.287

* The decompressor remembers now the working directory between sessions
* The decrypting tool remembers now the working directories between sessions
* The setup program correctly create the icons now when installing for the current user
* The FAQ has been updated

2005-10-12 Version 7.1.0.284

* Fixed a bug when zipping directories which contain some exception list. If the mask was of type SOMEDIR\*.* no files at all where included even files outside SOMEDIR. Fixed.
* Dutch FAQ updated

2005-10-05 Version 7.1.0.278

* The 2Gb limit for encrypting/decrypting operations has been eliminated. 
* The bug that prevented the program to decrypt files of size larger than 2Gb has been fixed.
* Korean language updated
* French translation updated
* The catalonian traduccion has been updated.
* Czech language updated.
* Norwegian language updated.
* One german translation has been updated.
* At last, an unified french translation has been added. All the other french translations are now substituted by this one.

2005-08-26 Version 7.0.1.275

* When the main window is protected by a password, there was an exception if the user doubleclicked the tray icon more than twice. Fixed.
* Dutch FAQ updated
* Fixed a bug when closing programs in a before or after backup event.
* Italian translation updated
* The decrypting tool clears now the log memo before decrypting
* Now you get a warning and error when you try to encrypt/decrypt a file larger than 2 GB

2005-08-19 Version 7.0.0.270

* The installer can now work automatically without any user input. An utility to create the setup script can be downloaded from my site.
* A bug in the installer always created the icons even when the user had this option checked off. 
* When aborting a job that had the shutdown box checked, the program shuted down the PC anyway. Fixed.
* Pressing Escape or Enter closes now the About box
* A bug in Delphi caused that some existing files were reported as "not found". Fixed (hopefully).
* A second italian translation has been included, thanks to Matteo Lanzoni
* A very incomplete hungarian translation has been added. Thanks to Manhiszvanna
* When deleting backup files, a message was shown about the user aborting the operation. Fixed
* Italian language file updated
* Chosing No compression sets now the Split property to "No split"
* A hidden registry setting to control the cache of the password has been added
* When a new task is created, the "Task name" edit box has now the focus

2005-08-03 Version 7.0.0.256 BETA

* Some users had weird installation errors. I have somewhat modified the setup program to prevent errors while writing to the system temporary directory.
* When the user protects the interface with a password, the password's cache will now expire when the interface minimizes
* Checking NAT fast track checks now also IPv6 extensions 

2005-08-03 Version 7.0.0.251 BETA

* Dutch help file added thanks to Frans van der Kolk
* In windows XP, a modal form sometimes was placed behind the main form. Fixed.
* Fixed an error with the AM/PM time format. The user interface didn't accept it.
* German translation updated
* A partial korean translation was added
* The FAQ has been revisited

2005-06-30 Version 7.0.0.243 BETA

* The engine worked painfully slow when no interface was available. Fixed.
* The decrypting plugin was corrupted in the last version. Fixed.
* A dutch version has been added. Thanks to Frans van der Kolk
* Three french translations have been updated.
* Greman translation updated

2005-06-30 Version 7.0.0.241 BETA
* The last version introduced some FTP problems when downloading, so I have rolled back some changes.
* Another german translation has been added.
* Czech language updated.

2005-06-29 Version 7.0.0.235 BETA

* The engine doesn't use the Borland memory manager anymore (it sucks when zipping huge numbers of files)
* The "range check error" when using FTP transfers should be solved now (hopfully)
* In some machines, SSL transfers didn't work at all. Fixed.
* The installation program distributes the SSL libraries now
* Spanish translation updated
* French translation updated
* German translation updated

2005-06-27 Version 7.0.0.230 BETA

* A bug in the decompresor has been fixed. The right string for Number of files is now shown.
* The user interface shows now only those tasks properties that are relevant to the selected task.
* The czech translation by Sulc Miroslav has been completed
* Two french language files have been updated.

2005-06-23 Version 7.0.0.227 BETA

* If the After backup events contains a Shutdown command, the backup history operations were not completly executed. Fixed. 
* The uninstalling program waits now 3 seconds before attempting to delete the engine
* The backup history stored the wrong file name when using zip files with advanced naming
* Another french translation added (thanks to Jérôme Lacambra)
* Portuguese language added (Thanks to Clayton Schirmer)
* Spanish language files updated
* In the backup properties dialog, double clicking in a local file or directory source or destination will now execute the file or open the directory.
* The list of the backup history scrolls down automatically to show the last added backup.
* Polish version added (Thanks to Tomasz Muszyñski)
* A french translation has been updated
* A partial czech translation by Sulc Miroslav has been added

2005-06-17 version  7.0.0.223  BETA

* When making an incremental compressed backup, and there is no need to compress any file, the program no longer shows the error "Couldn't find the compressed file".
* The final help file in french has been added (thanks to Emmanuel Brillot)
* When selecting the events "Execute" or "Execute and wait", the caption of the window was wrongly changed 

2005-06-16 version 7.0.0.220 BETA

* A bug has been fixed: Splitting a compressed incremental or differential backup always resulted in a full backup.
* Some small fixes in the help file
* The "Low priority copy thread" was too slow. This has been fixed.
* Fixed a bug. When downloading and compressing a non existing FTP directory, the current directory was wrongly zipped instead.

2005-06-15 Version 7.0.0.214 BETA

* Partial help translation to french (thanks to Emmanuel Brillot)
* Norwegian translation added (many thanks to Tarje Olderheim)
* Italian help file added (thanks to Fernando Sannazzaro)
* Italian help file updated

2005-06-14 Version 7.0.0.213 BETA

* Spanish language file updated
* The translator has now a search function
* The translator checks now that the number of parameters are equal in every side
* Some updates have been done in the french language files.

2005-06-13 Version 7.0.0.211 BETA

* One french translation has been updated
* The disabled buttons in the decompression tool look now OK.
* The remote backup tool has now a main menu
* Fixed a bug when displaying the task's properties in the remote backup tool
* The remote backup tool will not accept an empty password
* The user interface warns now if the task name contains one of the following characteres: /,\,*,?,|,:,",<,>
* Fixed the application icon for the CobBU.exe program
* A catalonian translation has been included, thanks to Pep Isern
* Some reorganization has been done in the Options dialog
* The FAQ has been updated

2005-06-12 Version 7.0.0.206 BETA

* Fixed a "Range check error" when downloaing files in some computers with High resolution Performance counters
* Fixed a bug when giving names to downloaded archives
* The tooltip of the application in the tray iocon will now show the name of the task that is being processed
* Ctrl+Z added as an alternative shortcut to show the interface
* Pointing to the name of the list in the status bar shows now the full path to the list

2005-06-10 Version 7.0.0.202 BETA

* Fixed the exception  "Format '%s' invalid or incompatible with argument" when compressing (introduced in the last build)
* Changing to a FTP remote directory that doesn't exists doesn't log an error now if the directory can be succesfully created


2005-06-09 Version 7.0.0.200 BETA

* A new option has been added to turn on/off the "first backup is full" feature
* The message "TLS is not available on the server. Trying to continue without TLS..." is not shown anymore, and it's not longer considered an error
* The interface to the Registry plugin was fixed
* The program logs now all the operations made with the source file's attributes
* A global shortcut can now be used to open the interface. Windows key + C is the default, but you can change that in the Options.
* The interface of the After backup plugin has been changed 
* Fixed the behavior of the plugin window in the user interface 
* Title meta tag of the help files have been fixed
* Fixed a bug in the about box. Clicking on the panel caused some labels to dissapear
* Copyright date fixed on the help file
* Changing the language translates not the "Active" or "Inactive" words in the status bar 

2005-06-07 Version 7.0.0.180 BETA

* French translation by Laurent Poulette added
* Another French translation by Emmanuelle Brillot added
* Another french translation by Philippe Rangeard added
* Italian translation by Fernando Sannazzaro added
* The Tasks tab is now correctly translated
* The "Engine no found" error is now ignored the first time
* Spelling errors fixed
* In the properties list box, the date AND time of the backup is now shown
* Some log strings are fixed
* Tab order in the Connect dialog of the remote tool fixed
* The Clear button in the Remote tool is now correctly tranlated
* The Password dialog in the Remote tool had 2 Cancel buttons. Corrected.
* The "Use icons in tabs" checkbox is now correctly translated.
* The error shown when the program failed to set the attributes are now verbose only
* If a "Before backup" plugin returns a negative number, the task will be ignored
* The remote backup properties show now the right strings
* The last used addresses of the remote backup work OK now
* Fixed a "problem" (caused by Windows) when an archive contains both a long and a short file name

2005-06-03 Version 7.0.0.177 BETA

* If the main copy method failed, it wrongly reported that "it couldn't delete a directory". Fixed.
* Fixed a problem when copying or encrypting read only files.


2005-06-02 Version 7.0.0.175 BETA

* The "Add task" popup menu will now be inactive if some task is selected
* Some spelling errors fixed
* Fixed the problem with the access violation when deleting backups

2005-06-01 Version 7.0.0.154 BETA is out

* Fixed a bug when zipping open files
* Spanish version added
* Fixed some small bugs

2005-05-16 Version 6.0 ALFA released. This is only a very primitive alfa version with lots of non functioning things

2005-05-15 Version 7 is Out

* Differential backups
* Now you can backup FROM a FTP server
* You can even backup from FTP to FTP
* The log file is now shown in real time
* SSL is now supported for FTP
* SQX compression is added
* A better and faster ZIP method is now used (zip64)
* Now you can limit the data transfer speed for FTPs

2005-01-28 Version 6.1.1.264
* Now you can use the program as a scheduler. Just add the source *DUMMY_SOURCE* using the "Add manually" button
* A new memory manager is used now to solve the Out of memory issue when compressing large archives
* A bug has been fixed with encryption and incremental backup. Encrypted backup respect now the archive attribute.
* Danish language added
* Norwegian language added
* Czech language updated
* German language updated

2005-01-14 Version 6.1.1.260

* Now you can split your files to a custom size
* An alternative french translation has been added
* English and swedish language has been corrected.
* The values for the split size have been changed. No problems fitting the media now, hopefully.
* The english help file has been corrected.

2004-12-16 Version 6.1.0.254
* Now you can have BOTH "Exclude files" AND "Include only" some files
* When zipping and uploading to an FTP the counter of the files used to show the real number +1. Fixed.
* When zipping several subtasks, the "root" of the zip will now be the parent directory of the first item. If you are updating existing files you could have duplicate items now because of this change. Delete your zip and make a whole backup first to be sure.
* A bug has been fixed when using "including" masks into a zip file.
* French language updated
* If the temporary directory doesn't exists, the program will now attempt to create it
* A bug has been fixed when sending the log to multiple recipients.

2004-12-08 Version 6.0.2.235

* You can now directly edit a source or destination line by double clicking on it.
* A new hidden setting has been introduced. You can now turn on/off the checking for the validity of the input in the source or destination box.
* The setup program is now 100 percent written by me
* Fixed a bug when dragging and dropping a folder in the Exclude dialog
* Before uploading a file, the program checks once more if a time out occurred on the server.
* A bug has fixed with non classical incremental FTP backup. It will now copy when the incremental flag is not set.

2004-12-01 Version 6.0.2.224
* The new unzipper can now be invoked from the Tools menu
* When splitting zip files AND sending them to a FTP, the file names will now be created correctly
* The unzip utility has been updated to handle the changes on the archives file name.
* A possible problem when checking the validity of the resulting file names has been fixed
* A bug has been fixed on the CRC checking procedure.
* A bug caused by the 3rd part zipping components has been fixed with a work around. File names that contained double extensions got cropped when splitting archives
* Added a hidden option to eliminate white spaces on dates in the file name. This is useful if your FTP server does have problems with spaces
* Some 3rd part components have been substituted by my own ones
* Slovak help file available as a download
* The setup program now creates a shortcut to the unzipper
* Serbian language (latin) has been added
* A new improved unzipper has been included. Now you can select the files to unzip.
* Alternative Prortuguese (BR) language added
* German ,Dutch and Czech languages updated
* Finish language added
* When using the abomination "Individual zipped subtasks" the "Kepp x copies" will have no effect now.
* Romanian language updated

2004-11-16 Version 6.0.2.209
* The user interface now shows the right size for large files > 4 GB
* The user interface uses now the API message box function when possible. 
* The setup program doesn't use any 3d-part components anymore, the early crashes were caused by the use of a bad 3rd part component
* The date/times values are now independent of the regional settings. The list will be converted to a new format
* Slovak language updated
* Portuguese (Brazil) language added

2004-11-11 Version 6.0.1.202

* Now you can right click to the tasks and choose Disable to disable/enable dem. No need to open a task only for this
* The installer's behavior has been modified a little 
* The uninstaller will now respect the extra plugins and languages installed after the setup
* Fixed a bug when the engine would freeze in service mode while compressing afile open exclusively be another application.
* Dutch language added
* Czech language added
* Portuguese language added
* Nonsense language added
* Swedish language added
* A plugin (CobLazy) was created. Available from the website but NOT in the distro

2004-10-06 Version 6.0.0.200

* Fixed another bug with the DateTime picker 

2004-10-05 Version 6.0.0.194

* Exclusions list logics has been rewritten
* If the log file was empty, an exception would happen when displaying the log file. Fixed.
* The directory size now shows th RIGHT size
* Romanian language added 
* Slovakian language added
* Fixed a bug with the DateTime picker 
* A totally new setup program was build

2004-10-01 Version 6.0.0.187

* VERSION 6.0 RELEASED** It's all new. Period.
* Support for Zip64 for huge zip files
* Zip files can be splitted now
* Strong encrypting procedures to secure your backups. 
  Uses Blowfish (128-bit), Rijndael (128-bit) or DES (64-bit)
* The user can change the font of the user interface
* A plugin architecture was developed and the "Decrypting" plugin was created
* The interprocess communication is done using TCP/IP
* Remote control is now posible using TCP/IP
* Backup one source to multiple destination
* Local and FTP backup
* 3 methods of copying files for more reliability
* Everything is coded from scratch
* Avanced users can modify almost every detail of the backup process 

2004-01-09 No new version

* Finish traslation added as a separate download from my site
* Spanish help file added as a separate download from my site
* Fixed dutch translation as a separate download from my site
* Romanian  translation added as a separate download from my site
* Added danish translation as a separate download from my site

2003-09-20 Version 5.2.1.0

* Fixed an "Index out of bounds" error on the new Select folder dialog
* A quick fix to eliminate the bug when compressing files with accented characteres in the file name 
(a more complete fix for this problem comes in future versions)


2003-09-11 Version 5.2.0.0

* Now you can store files in the zip archive using the OEM codepage for compatibility with WinZip and other programs
* Now you can select whole directories in the exclusion list
* New hungarian translation included (full)
* Fixed a bug on drag and drop in the properties dialog box
* A debug mode was introduced.
* Fixed the error: ZipMsgXX.res is probably not linked to the executable

2003-09-06 Version 5.1.4.0

* Some more changes introduced in the Copy procedure.Hopefully the "Invalid window handle" error will be gone now.

2003-08-23 Version 5.1.3.0

* Fixed a bug in the Copy procedure. 

2003-08-23 Version 5.1.2.0

* The old zip method has been dropped and completly replaced by the new one 
* A new improved german translation is done
* Portuguese-pt translation added
* Hungarian translation added (somewhat incomplete, but usable)

2003-08-10 Version 5.1.1.0

* Encrypt procedure for the new zip method fixed

2003-08-10 Version 5.1.0.0

* An alternative zip method has been implemented using the INFOZIP libraries. Hopefully all zip and CRC problems will be gone now. (Note that this is NOT the default compression method. You need to select it from the options)
* German translation added
* Chech language added.

2003-07-26 Version 5.0.3.0

* FTP transfers uses now the inclusion/exclusion list
* All the elements on the interface use the default charset
* Lithuanian translation included


2003-07-13 Version 5.0.2.0

* You can now select multiple directories for the source file. An alternative "standard" dialog is also included due to problems of the new dialog on double-byte systems
* A new type of "dummy" source has been added(Pressing Ctrl-Alt-D on the source edit box)
* Fixed an error in the converting utility. When converting a list from version 4 to 5 an inclusion list was converted as an exclusion
* I'm back using the old copy method and not using streams anymore: too much problems
* Some changes has been made on the english, swedish, french and italian translations
* Dutch translation added

2003-07-04 Version 5.0.1.0

* The select folder dialog was giving a lot of problems on chinese and other double-byte Windows, so I am back into the standard select folder dialog.To select multiple directories you must now use drag'n'drop from the explorer.
* Drag'n'drop is now supported directly into the New backup window and not only into the main window.
* If the source contains more than one item and you are compressing, the zip file will now always store absolute paths. 
* A bug in the installer has been fixed when setting the autostart keys on the registry 
* The program now correctly re-writes read-only files
* The program copies now the file attributes

2003-06-30 Version 5.0

* The backup engine has been rewrited from scrach
* User interface has been partially re-designed
* A main menu has been added for users without mouse
* The password for the user interface is now cached in memory 1 minute
* Multi-language support 
* The program no longer hangs if the current list doesn't exists
* Support for backup to a FTP  server
* A backup item can now contain multiple files/directories
* Incremental backups are now possible on zip files
* Fixed a bug when selecting shortcuts
* Fixed a bug on the exclude/include dialog box
* Some SMTP servers verifies by the sender e-mail
  {Normally the from address will be the same of the destination e.mail
  but if the user writes an adress as the SenderName, use THIS as the
  SenderAddress}
* The copy procedure has been COMPLETLY rewrited, using streams now
* The incremental procedure uses the Archive bit now and not the timestamp of the file
* Now you can give the backup items a name
* Help file converted to HTML format
* The backup list is now executed in a sequencial way and not at the same time on different threads
* On the Before-After backup events you can now enter pauses
* A new kind of backup (manual) has been introduced
* A timer event will NOT start now at time=0
* The select folder dialog allows multiselection now
* The installation program uses now a modified version of Inno Setup
* An utility to convert backup lists from version 3 and 4 to version 5 has been included
* An utility to translate thr ptogram has been included 
* The setup utility grants now privileges to logon as a service to the user if the program is installed as a service
* A bug fixed with zipped files. When zipping a big file (>700 Mb) the zip file would become corrupted sometimes. This has been fixed.

2002-11-26 Version 4.1.9.0

* A bug fixed. The "store absolute paths" option works OK now.
* The SMTP password is hidden now on the user interface.

2002-11-15  Version 4.1.8.0

* The day "Wednesday" is now correctly displayed on the grid.
* When one or more items on the grid where deleted, the number of files and size were not
updated. Fixed.
* The grid shows now the number of files and the total size to backup, considering the
exclude/include list.

2002-11-06 Version 4.1.7.0

* When calculating the total file sizes, the user interface doesn't lock now.
The calculating code runs in another thread now.

2002-11-05 Version 4.1.6.0

* On XP multiple instances cannot be started now with "fast user switch".
* Hopefully a bug has been fixed on the service-interface interprocess communication
* The "Low priority" option for copy thread has been re-written
* The progress bars indicate now when one big file is beeng zipped or copied by 
changing the caption. This way the user gets the picture that something is going on.

2002-10-30 Version 4.1.5.0

* A REAL command line utility has now been included (cobline.exe). If you want to
do a manual backup from the command line, use this program (cobline.exe) and NOT CobBU.exe.
The arguments are the name of the list to backup (using quotes if the name contains spaces)
and and optional /q to close the program when it executes.
Example:
cobline.exe "c:\%s\MainList.lst" /Q
If you don't write a file name, you will be prompted to enter one (don't use quotes this time,
if you are prompted by the program).
This command line utility creates a separated log file (logline.txt).

2002-10-28 Version 4.1.0.0

* Added a function to "clone" backup items on the list. (right click on any item)
* Live update writes now to the log file. A new version is logged as "error"
to get your attention
* Now it is possible to change the priority of the copying threads. Sometimes when executing
several  backup threads, the performance of the system will go down. If you don't mind a 
longer backup time, change the priority to Low. The default value is Normal.
* The "Day of the Week" combo box is now a drop down list.

2002-10-15 Version 4.0.0.0
A new major version of %s if out.
* The program engine has been re-written from scratch.
* Two new events has been added to every backup : a "Before backup" event and an "After backup".
These events are useful if you need to automatically close some program before the backup and 
open it again after the backup.Please, read the help file for more information about some
problems when using this feature as a service.
* Every backup item has now it's own unique ID
* The program checks now if a file is in use by another program BEFORE it tries 
to copy it. This way you will no longer get a destination file with 0 bytes in 
it.
* You can now sort the items in the list view by Name, Size, Source, Attributes, Kind or Destination.
* The exclude/include list accepts now wildcards (ex:  *.doc, cob?.ex?, etc)
* The log book's engine is much more robust now
* The inter-process communication between the engine and the user interface works MUCH better now.
* Two progress bars show now the status of the zipping and copying operations.
* The program can now schedule Windows restart-shutdown events.
* Better looking user interface
* An emergency "Abort backup" function added (experimental)
* Multi-language support added for future translations.

2002-07-07 Version 3.9.2.0
* The "information window" has been substituted by a new status bar.
* Help file updated

2002-07-07 Version 3.9.1.0
* All the icons in the user interface has been replaced in favor of better looking ones.
* The password for zip files and for the user interface are now two separated options
* A bug has been fixed when selecting multiple files on a new event
* The list view shows now only one field for the attributes: Zip, Overwrite, Incremental and Include subdirectories.
* About box style changed to a standard one

2002-06-27 Version 3.9.0.5
* The source code has been cleaned up and optimized a bit more
* A new button added to create an empty list

2002-06-26 Version 3.9.0.3
* A new option is available to store the absolute path of the files in the zip
* Fixed an intermitent bug when storing the coordinates of the user interface into the ini file

2002-06-26 Version 3.9.0.2
* Some optimizations done
* Ini file for the backup progress window is now a separated file
* The total number of files and the total size is now correctly calculated
* A new item ID has been introduced for future use
* A bug has been fixed when adding multiple files at the same time
* Some visual changes in the option dialog

2002-06-24 Version 3.9.9.1
* A special way to handle eventual exceptions added to the user interface.

2002-06-19 Version 3.9.0.0 
* A new fonster shows the status of all active threads (everything that is going when backing up)
* The status bar shows now the total size of the set and the total number of files to backup
* A bug fixed (a Quit message was posted to the engine before the exit confirmation)
* NO MAJOR UPDATES OF THIS PROGRAM WILL BE DONE.

2002-06-19 Version 3.8.7.6
* Fixed an issue with incremental backups. Newer files could be replaced by older ones.

2002-06-17 Version 3.8.7.5 released
* A new button (Delete log file) added.
* Now you can set the time when the log file will be mailed. You are no more restricted to 22:00.

2002-05-07 Version 3.8.7.0
* The user interface remerber now the last position and the columns width
* Now you can manually backup separate items. There is no need to manually backup all the items at once.
* The destination and source edit box can be manually editet by double clicking.

2002-05-02 Version 3.8.6.6
Fixed another problem with date conversions. Hopefully it works now on all systems

2002-04-29 Version 3.8.6.4
Fixed a problem when Windows uses the date format DD-MMM-YYY (ex: 23-DEC-02).


2002-04-24 Version 3.8.6.3
* A bug fixed. When the program tried to copy a file and failed a dialog box was shown.
This is now fixed.
* The installation program gives a warning if an old version is found on your system

2002-04-24 Version 3.8.6.2 released
* Support for Windows XP themes
* Uses standard Windows colors now (by request)
* Supports drag'n'drop from Windows Explorer
* You can now select multiple files from the "Open File" dialog box
* The program remember your last destination folder
* The zip procedures support now OEM conversion (PKZIP compatible)
* Installation program works MUCH better now.
* When running as an application, the program supports parameters now.
The parameters are:
/backupnow -backups the active list
/nogui  - don't show the user interface
filename (no / is allowed. If the file name contains spaces, use ")-loads the list filename
Exemple:
CobBU.exe "c:\%s\mainlist.lst" /backupnow

2002-04-17 Version 3.8.5.1 released
* Incremental backup implemented
* Now you can add a mask to exclude/include certain extensions
* I don't use CopyFile anymore. I use SHFileOperation to backup files and directories.

2002-03-21 Version 3.7.0.1 released
* Live update added
* A bug fixed when zipping files
* The zipping thread was nearly completly re-writted
* A new enhanced ini file is created now for new features
* Double click bug fixed in the list view

2002-03-19 Version 3.6.0.2 released
* Fixed a nasty bug when backuping a root directory (ex j:\)
* A toolbutton to show the log file added to the interface
* Borland Delphi 6 is shown in the about box now
* A warning is shown when a backup is going on and the user click on Backup Now
* Log file information is much clear now
* Installation program logics changed .

2002-02-03 Version 3.5.0.1 released
* Added an animated icon to the tray interface, indicating when a backup is going on
* When trying to quit the program and a backup is going on, a warning will be diplayed


2002-01-28 Version 3.0.0.25
* Fixed Access violation while running in Windows Millenium.
* The timer thread could not be terminated while sleeping.
When the user try to run multiple instances, itbring the interface to the front and doen't show the old message box "Application already running".
* This file "history.txt" was added.

**
2002-01-18 Version 3.0.0.21 
* Button "Backup now" added. Fixed a access violation in Windows Millenium with the SelectDirectory function.
* Fixed a bug in the installation program when uninstalling 
the service

**
2002-01-06 %s 3.0 released.

**
2001-09-12 CobBackUp 2.0.0.18 released. Some bugs fixed.

**
2001-08-14 CobBackup 2.0 released 

**
2000-11-04 CobBackup 1.0 released
