%PROGRAMNAME% APPLICATION AND SERVICE MODE

© Copyright 2000-2005 by %AUTHOR%
All rights reserved

%PROGRAMNAME% is a multi-threaded program that can be used to schedule and 
backup your files and directories from their original location to other 
directories/drives in the same computer or other computer in your network. 
FTP backup is also supported in both ways (upload and download). 

%PROGRAMNAME% exists in two different versions: application and service.

You can automatically backup your files once, daily, weekly, monthly, Yearly
or on a timer basis. 

You can also save and open lists with different backup file sets. 

The program creates a log file which optionally can be mailed to you
automatically.

%PROGRAMNAME% can be used on Windows NT/2000/XP/2003,Vista or other NT based system. 

%PROGRAMNAME% has integrated compression capabilities, using the Zip64 or the SQX algorithms.

All the functions in the program can optionally be password protected and the 
backup files can be encrypted using one of the following methods:
RSA (1024-bit), Blowfish (128-bit), Rijndael (128-bit) or DES (64-bit)
 
Backup to and from FTP servers is possible.

Install and uninstall

Important: running under NT/2000/XP/2003/Vista, you must have administrative  
privileges to install the program as a service. 
If you have an old **major** version of the program running NEVER INSTALL the 
new version into the old version's directory. Uninstall the old version first.

To properly install %PROGRAMNAME%, simply run the setup program. 
Choose a directory to install, for example C:\%PROGRAMNAME% and select 
the installation mode:

As a service:  You will be prompted if you want to 
run the service under the system account or other account. If you are 
accessing network resources, you cannot run the service under the 
LocalSystem account. Read more about this in the help file.

As an application, autostart for any user: this option installs the 
program as an application, and starts it automatically when any user 
logs on. 

As an application, autostart the current user: option installs the
program as an application, and starts it automatically when the current 
user logs on. 

As an application, no autostart: The application must be manually 
started from the icon in the start- menu. 

To uninstall the program, go to the Control panel- Add/delete program 
and select %PROGRAMNAME%.

%PROGRAMNAME% is Freeware even for commercial use. You are allowed to copy, 
use and distribute the program, but only in the original package . 
